<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Vera Shur | Portfolio</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Vera Shur&#039;s Design Portfolio</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 05:28:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>+ Shelf</title>
		<link>/shelf/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 05:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=753</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[+ Shelf Artist-in-Residency at Autodesk 2015 A prototype for an easy-to-assemble shelving system that can be customized to suit one&#8217;s space and contents. The 3d printed +&#8217;s hold together each individual cubby. Gaps between each cubby, equal to the thickness of each +, give the shelves the feeling of floating in space.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>+ Shelf</h4>
<h5>Artist-in-Residency at Autodesk</h5>
<h5>2015</h5>
<p></p>
<p>A prototype for an easy-to-assemble shelving system that can be customized to suit one&#8217;s space and contents. The 3d printed +&#8217;s hold together each individual cubby. Gaps between each cubby, equal to the thickness of each +, give the shelves the feeling of floating in space.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cross Tenon Coat Rack</title>
		<link>/cross-tenon-coat-rack/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 23:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=763</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Cross Tenon Coat Rack Artist-in-Residency at Autodesk 2015 This project explores the possibilities presented by 3d printing to advance joinery techniques beyond what was possible to do in wood alone. The joint holding together this coat rack plays on the traditional wedged tenon used in woodworking.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Cross Tenon Coat Rack</h4>
<h5>Artist-in-Residency at Autodesk</h5>
<h5>2015</h5>
<p></p>
<p>This project explores the possibilities presented by 3d printing to advance joinery techniques beyond what was possible to do in wood alone. The joint holding together this coat rack plays on the traditional wedged tenon used in woodworking. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Tap Tables</title>
		<link>/the-tap-tables/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 06:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=723</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Tap Tables Artist-in-Residency at Autodesk 2015 These investigations focus on how 3D-printed joints can replace wood joinery in furniture assembly. The 3D prints explore formal means of expression unique to the properties of the material, rather than attempting to mimic traditional wooden joints. The table was first made using an Objet 3D printer, and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>The Tap Tables</h4>
<h5>Artist-in-Residency at Autodesk</h5>
<h5>2015</h5>
<p></p>
<p>These investigations focus on how 3D-printed joints can replace wood joinery in furniture assembly. The 3D prints explore formal means of expression unique to the properties of the material, rather than attempting to mimic traditional wooden joints.</p>
<p>The table was first made using an Objet 3D printer, and then &#8211; to create a more accessible design &#8211; adapted to be printed on a Dremel Ideabuilder, without the need for any support material. </p>
<p>To make your own, go here: http://www.instructables.com/id/Table-with-3D-Printed-Joints/</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two Weekend Table</title>
		<link>/two-weekend-table/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 04:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=695</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Two Weekend Table 2014 A walnut kitchen table built over the course of two weekends. For instructions on how to make one for yourself, go here: http://www.instructables.com/id/The-Two-Weekend-Table/.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>The Two Weekend Table</h4>
<h5>2014</h5>
<p></p>
<p>A walnut kitchen table built over the course of two weekends.</p>
<p>For instructions on how to make one for yourself, go here: http://www.instructables.com/id/The-Two-Weekend-Table/.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Incubator Space</title>
		<link>/collaborative-workspace/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 03:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Environments]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=668</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Incubator Space VITAL environments, Inc. Role: Lead Designer &#038; Project Manager 2014 How can you make a space that fosters an innovation community? Located in downtown Honolulu, this co-working space for a clean energy accelerator and its portfolio companies seeks to provide a flexible work environment and showcase the breadth and reach of its community. [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Incubator Space</h4>
<h5>VITAL environments, Inc.</h5>
<h5>Role: Lead Designer &#038; Project Manager</h5>
<h5>2014</h5>
<p></p>
<p>How can you make a space that fosters an innovation community? </p>
<p>Located in downtown Honolulu, this co-working space for a clean energy accelerator and its portfolio companies seeks to provide a flexible work environment and showcase the breadth and reach of its community. Through deep engagement with the client and stakeholders, we crafted a space that reflected the organization&#8217;s mission and values, and made a home for its team.</p>
<p>As project lead, responsibilities included the design of the space and custom furniture elements, choosing furnishings and finishes, UX design, documentation, working closely with the client and contractors, and construction administration.</p>
<p>Images and video courtesy of VITAL environments, Inc.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Outdoor Amphitheater</title>
		<link>/outdoor-amphitheater/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 06:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=403</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Outdoor Amphitheater Mark Cavagnero Associates Architects Role: Project Architect 2012-ongoing How can an outdoor amphitheater complement its natural setting and create an encompassing environment for its patrons? The pavilion&#8217;s heavy concrete walls contrast with the lightness of the canopy and ground the pavilion in the landscape, while also providing a noise buffer from the surrounding [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Outdoor Amphitheater</h4>
<h5>Mark Cavagnero Associates Architects</h5>
<h5>Role: Project Architect</h5>
<h5>2012-ongoing</h5>
<p></p>
<p>How can an outdoor amphitheater complement its natural setting and create an encompassing environment for its patrons?</p>
<p>The pavilion&#8217;s heavy concrete walls contrast with the lightness of the canopy and ground the pavilion in the landscape, while also providing a noise buffer from the surrounding roads. The venue&#8217;s flexible design makes it suitable for a variety of performances. The intimacy of the table seating at the terraces is designed to suit orchestra and dance, while the expansive, gently-sloping lawn allows for increased capacity for rock concerts. To stay within a tight budget, all architectural elements also serve structural and acoustical functions.</p>
<p>As project architect, responsibilities include production of all drawings, renderings and 3d models, and coordination with acoustical, theatrical, structural, landscape, MEP, and civil consultants.</p>
<p>Renderings courtesy of Mark Cavagnero Associates Architects.<br />
Site plan courtesy of SWA Group.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crissy Field Commissary</title>
		<link>/crissy-field-commissary/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 20:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Environments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Graphic Design]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=363</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Crissy Field Commissary Mark Cavagnero Associates Architects Role: Designer 2012 What are the walls of an outdoor room? How can a building function on the scale of the street and on the scale of the city? This proposal for the renovation of the existing commissary seeks to fill a gap in the rhythm along Mason [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Crissy Field Commissary</h4>
<h5>Mark Cavagnero Associates Architects</h5>
<h5>Role: Designer</h5>
<h5>2012</h5>
<p></p>
<p>What are the walls of an outdoor room?<br />
How can a building function on the scale of the street and on the scale of the city?</p>
<p>This proposal for the renovation of the existing commissary seeks to fill a gap in the rhythm along Mason Street, which is otherwise composed of long, white buildings with gabled roofs. The design integrates this simple form into a new addition fronting the street, while maintaining the existing column-and-frame structure in the renovated portion of the building. </p>
<p>As the designer for this proposal, responsibilities included production of all images. Blocks of color and sans-serif text were used to evoke the simple forms of the existing buildings on the site and its expansive natural setting. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>San Francisco Opera</title>
		<link>/san-francisco-opera/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 01:08:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=619</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[War Veterans Memorial Interior Renovation New Performance Space and Offices for the San Francisco Opera Mark Cavagnero Associates Role: Designer 2012 Responsible for plans, sections, interior elevations, and details for Design Development set.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>War Veterans Memorial Interior Renovation</h4>
<h5>New Performance Space and Offices for the San Francisco Opera</h5>
<h5>Mark Cavagnero Associates</h5>
<h5>Role: Designer</h5>
<h5>2012</h5>
<p></p>
<p>Responsible for plans, sections, interior elevations, and details for Design Development set.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Walnut Creek Residence</title>
		<link>/walnut-creek-residence/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 19:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=357</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Walnut Creek Residence Sole Designer 2011-ongoing How can a porch open up a house? The design for an outdoor living room and porch creates visual and physical connections between the existing residence and its backyard, while providing a shield from the sun. The sliding planes of the roofs compliment the horizontality of the ranch house [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Walnut Creek Residence</h4>
<h5>Sole Designer</h5>
<h5>2011-ongoing</h5>
<p></p>
<p>How can a porch open up a house?</p>
<p>The design for an outdoor living room and porch creates visual and physical connections between the existing residence and its backyard, while providing a shield from the sun. The sliding planes of the roofs compliment the horizontality of the ranch house and create distinct zones of habitation.</p>
<p>As sole designer, responsibilities included in-depth design sessions with the clients and all aspects of design, from concept to material selection.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monumental Lightness</title>
		<link>/monumental-lightness/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 04:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Environments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Graphic Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=41</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Monumental Lightness Harvard Graduate School of Design Master of Architecture Thesis Advisor: John Hong 2011 How can a monument to the past remain relevant in the present? The emergence of the digital archive has engendered a mania to gather, catalogue, and store everything without regard for its relative value and place within history. Though archiving [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Monumental Lightness</h4>
<h5>Harvard Graduate School of Design</h5>
<h5>Master of Architecture Thesis</h5>
<h5>Advisor: John Hong</h5>
<h5>2011</h5>
<p></p>
<p>How can a monument to the past remain relevant in the present?</p>
<p>The emergence of the digital archive has engendered a mania to gather, catalogue, and store everything without regard for its relative value and place within history. Though archiving can be seen as an act of preservation, it is also an act of destruction. Entombing information offers a means of destroying it to liberate the future from the past. Thus, forgetting is the companion of archiving. Andreas Huyssen writes of a “major and puzzling contradiction in our culture. The undisputed waning of history and historical consciousness, the lament about political, social and cultural amnesia&#8230;have been accompanied in the past decade and a half by a memory boom of unprecedented proportions.” What is missing from this odd partnership of the past and the future is any sense of the present, of the processes of change, of the awareness of existing in a particular cultural moment.</p>
<p>In this proposal for a language archive, the structure of the building acts as a metaphor for the content it contains. The tensile pods holding each language library are aurally and structurally interlinked, creating reverberations throughout the archive that demonstrate the languages’ connectivity to one another and their continual evolution.</p>
<p> A traditional archive mediates content through a curator. The digital archive, a recent typology, contains no hierarchy. This building defines an alternate relationship between archivist, content, and audience. Within it, architecture acts as the curator between the digital archive and the public.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mobile Market</title>
		<link>/mobile-market/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 04:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Environments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Products]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=44</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Mobile Market Harvard Graduate School of Design Studio: Post-disaster Architecure Critics: Shigeru Ban and Danielle Etzler In collaboration with Christina Cho 2010 How can a simple object spur a region&#8217;s recovery effort after a natural disaster? A deployable market composed of re-configurable canopies charts a series of paths through the old city of L&#8217;Aquila, Italy, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Mobile Market</h4>
<h5>Harvard Graduate School of Design</h5>
<h5>Studio: Post-disaster Architecure</h5>
<h5>Critics: Shigeru Ban and Danielle Etzler</h5>
<h5>In collaboration with Christina Cho</h5>
<h5>2010</h5>
<p></p>
<p>How can a simple object spur a region&#8217;s recovery effort after a natural disaster?</p>
<p>A deployable market composed of re-configurable canopies charts a series of paths through the old city of L&#8217;Aquila, Italy, which was recently devastated by an earthquake. The market brings in much needed commerce and encourages residents to return to the city center.</p>
<p>The individual umbrellas can be fully opened and placed in the piazzas to form a field of arches that house a market. In their closed positions, the umbrellas can be placed along streets to chart the course of the rebuilding effort. The umbrellas are primary constructed of cheap, easily obtainable materials: pvc piping, plywood, and kite parts. Components that require specialized materials and machinery, such as the stainless steel joints, are designed to be small and packed flat to ship. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Re-fabricating Fisac</title>
		<link>/re-fabricating-fisac/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 04:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=36</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Refabricating Fisac Harvard Graduate School of Design Refabricating Tectonic Prototypes Critic: Leire Asensio Villoria In collaboration with Sean Corriel, Andrew Domnitz 2010 When can a beam be more than structural? Drawing inspiration from the Catalan architect Miguel Fisac&#8217;s light diffusing beam sections, this project seeks to invent a parametrically adaptable beam profile that can be [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Refabricating Fisac</h4>
<h5>Harvard Graduate School of Design</h5>
<h5>Refabricating Tectonic Prototypes</h5>
<h5>Critic: Leire Asensio Villoria</h5>
<h5>In collaboration with Sean Corriel, Andrew Domnitz</h5>
<h5>2010</h5>
<p></p>
<p>When can a beam be more than structural?</p>
<p>Drawing inspiration from the Catalan architect Miguel Fisac&#8217;s light diffusing beam sections, this project seeks to invent a parametrically adaptable beam profile that can be shaped to optimize various structural and lighting needs. Whereas Fisac’s beams are uni-directional, the proposed system functions multi-dimensionally. It is structurally adaptive to resist moment and torque brought about by curved conditions. The system is further optimized for natural light levels and solar orientation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Landscape as Animation</title>
		<link>/landscape-as-animation/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 04:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Environments]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=29</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Landscape as Animation Harvard Graduate School of Design Instructor: Joshua Mosley 2010 What aspects of landscape are revealed through motion? This series of animations explores environmental rhythms by means of inserting animated objects into natural scenes. Their purpose is to exaggerate and call attention to otherwise imperceptible motion within our everyday surroundings.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Landscape as Animation</h4>
<h5>Harvard Graduate School of Design</h5>
<h5>Instructor: Joshua Mosley</h5>
<h5>2010</h5>
<p></p>
<p>What aspects of landscape are revealed through motion?</p>
<p>This series of animations explores environmental rhythms by means of inserting animated objects into natural scenes. Their purpose is to exaggerate and call attention to otherwise imperceptible motion within our everyday surroundings. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PlaySound PlayGround</title>
		<link>/playsound/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 04:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Environments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=24</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[PlaySound Playground Harvard Graduate School of Design Moment of the Monument Professor: Jeffrey Schnapp In collaboration with Julian Wu 2010 How can a monument communicate with children through play? According to the writer Robert Musil, the fate of monuments is to be “conspicuously inconspicuous.” The PlaySound PlayGround, a monument to the endangered languages of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>PlaySound Playground</h4>
<h5>Harvard Graduate School of Design</h5>
<h5>Moment of the Monument</h5>
<h5>Professor: Jeffrey Schnapp</h5>
<h5>In collaboration with Julian Wu</h5>
<h5>2010</h5>
<p></p>
<p>How can a monument communicate with children through play?</p>
<p>According to the writer Robert Musil, the fate of monuments is to be “conspicuously inconspicuous.” The PlaySound PlayGround, a monument to the endangered languages of the Caucasus, remains meaningful by being “inconspicuously conspicuous.” The PlaySound encourages active participation and engagement with its subject matter by integrating itself into the daily life of children. Its dual functionality as a monument and a playground creates an ambient learning experience without calling attention to itself. It does not rely on written plagues or static symbols to impart meaning. Rather, it creates a dynamic, interactive atmosphere that orchestrates and accommodates the way that children play.</p>
<p>Children’s stories are often the most effective vehicles for passing on cultural traditions and maintaining an active language. The PlaySound consists of a series of thirty-four grassy hills, alluding to the topographical variety of the region, each referencing an active North Caucasian language and the recently extinct language of Ubykh. Sensors built into each hill detect weight and movement on the playground equipment and activate a sound-scape of the hill’s particular language in ways specific to its degree of endangerment. Voices reciting fables and stories from each language are projected from hidden speakers in the ground. Because the sensors are sensitive to the number of people on the PlaySound at any given time, as well as their relatives positions, the experience of the monument is always different, and every journey taken through it encounters a unique exposure to sound. </p>
<p>The layout of the hills clusters the three language groups together so that children can register their similarities even if they may not understand the languages themselves. The relative height and isolation of each hill correlates to the number of people left who speak each language as their mother tongue. The tallest, steepest hill, located in the center of the playground, represents Ubykh. By delicately privileging the endangered languages by assigning them to higher hills with greater views, the PlaySound hopes to spark curiosity and elevate the status of these languages in the minds of the children. Ultimately, the monument hopes to curtail, and even reverse, the process of language extinction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Residential Studio</title>
		<link>/residential-studio/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 00:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=611</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Residential Studio Lon Design Role: Designer 2010 Responsible for schematic design and permit set for small residential studio in Cambridge, MA.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Residential Studio</h4>
<h5>Lon Design</h5>
<h5>Role: Designer</h5>
<h5>2010</h5>
<p></p>
<p>Responsible for schematic design and permit set for small residential studio in Cambridge, MA.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lemons of the Sorrentine Peninsula</title>
		<link>/lemons-of-the-sorrentine-peninsula/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2010 18:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=545</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lemons of the Sorrentine Peninsula: An Integrated Cultural Landscape Harvard Graduate School of Design Penny White Travel and Research Grant In collaboration with Julian Wu 2010 How does agriculture influence culture? How has lemon farming along the Sorrentine Peninsula symbiotically evolved alongside the region&#8217;s urban development? The lemon gardens of the Sorrentino-Amalfitana Peninsula represent a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Lemons of the Sorrentine Peninsula: An Integrated Cultural Landscape</h4>
<h5>Harvard Graduate School of Design</h5>
<h5>Penny White Travel and Research Grant</h5>
<h5>In collaboration with Julian Wu</h5>
<h5>2010</h5>
<p></p>
<p>How does agriculture influence culture?<br />
How has lemon farming along the Sorrentine Peninsula symbiotically evolved alongside the region&#8217;s urban development?</p>
<p>The lemon gardens of the Sorrentino-Amalfitana Peninsula represent a complete integration and co-evolution of an agricultural product with its physical and cultural environment. Over the last 300 years, the demands of lemon tree cultivation have morphed the landscape of the peninsula and influenced patterns of settlement in the area. Lemon tree farming has impacted the physical development of the towns along the coastline, from the density of the population to the shapes of the individual dwellings, through its proliferation and dependency on terraced ground. Though lemon farming in the region is difficult and labor-intensive on account of its severe topography and occasionally adverse weather conditions, the lemon trees play a crucial role in their physical environment by counteracting hydrological instability and erosion of the soil, a phenomenon common in similar areas of Italy. </p>
<p>Biological, social, economic, and institutional factors were evaluated in order to identify sustainable methods of preservation and possible future adaptation. Connections between lemon farming, landscape, and architectural expression were studied to determine the relationships among these elements that make the area an ecologically and culturally successful example of agricultural semi-urbanization.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The New Gate</title>
		<link>/the-new-gate/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 04:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=52</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The New Gate: A Train Station for Istanbul Harvard Graduate School of Design Options Studio Critic: Hashim Sarkis 2009 How can a new train station connecting the two halves of Istanbul reorganize and reorient the city? The design for this train station functions as an intermodel urban connector, nested within the surrounding neighborhoods and imposing [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>The New Gate: A Train Station for Istanbul</h4>
<h5>Harvard Graduate School of Design</p>
<h5>
<h5>Options Studio</h5>
<h5>Critic: Hashim Sarkis</h5>
<h5>2009</h5>
<p></p>
<p>How can a new train station connecting the two halves of Istanbul reorganize and reorient the city?</p>
<p>The design for this train station functions as an intermodel urban connector, nested within the surrounding neighborhoods and imposing its own order back onto the city. Like the Grand Bazaar, the station is both a continuation of Istanbul’s streets and an autonomous object within the urban fabric. it is able to project its own identity into the city while remaining embedded within the local scale. </p>
<p>The station makes legible the passenger flows that are collected, reorganized, and diverted to their desired modes of transit.  The building acts as an aggregation of filaments that bundle or unravel, based on the meeting or diverging of major passenger corridors. To ensure efficiency and clarity, movement of people is highly controlled up until the moment they are released to the train platforms, at which point the regulated environment gives way to an open space of freedom and informality. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Science and Design Institute</title>
		<link>/institute-for-science-and-design/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 04:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=78</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Institute for Interfaces in Science and Design Harvard Graduate School of Design Studio II Critic: Mariana Ibanez 2008 What happens when science interfaces with design? This project explores the intersection of typically isolated programs and the resulting interaction between visitors and research fellows, exhibitions and lab spaces. New volumetric configurations and programmatic opportunities are created [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Institute for Interfaces in Science and Design</h4>
<h5>Harvard Graduate School of Design</h5>
<h5>Studio II</h5>
<h5>Critic: Mariana Ibanez</h5>
<h5>2008</h5>
<p></p>
<p>What happens when science interfaces with design?</p>
<p>This project explores the intersection of typically isolated programs and the resulting interaction between visitors and research fellows, exhibitions and lab spaces. New volumetric configurations and programmatic opportunities are created when the boundaries of spaces holding discrete functions overlap. Circulation exists in excess to provide choice to visitors, but ultimately the building controls the inhabitant, drawing him back toward the focal areas of activity. The flow through the building can be likened to the pendulum of a clock, constantly oscillating from side to side but always coming to rest in the center.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Undergraduate Housing</title>
		<link>/undergraduate-housing/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2008 04:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=58</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Harvard Undergraduate Housing Harvard Graduate School of Design Studio III Critic: John Hong 2008 How can a student dorm encourage greater awareness and interaction among its residents? This dorm integrates public and private programs through section. Large common programs are slotted into either end of the building. Residences located nearest to these public programs are [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Harvard Undergraduate Housing</h4>
<h5>Harvard Graduate School of Design</h5>
<h5>Studio III</h5>
<h5>Critic: John Hong</h5>
<h5>2008</h5>
<p></p>
<p>How can a student dorm encourage greater awareness and interaction among its residents?</p>
<p>This dorm integrates public and private programs through section. Large common programs are slotted into either end of the building. Residences located nearest to these public programs are deformed sectionally and thus share multiple interfacial surfaces. Residential suites interact with circulation by means of common spaces located on bridges spanning the primary circulation of the building. An ambient awareness develops between inhabitants, day students, and the public through sectional manipulation and an abundance of circulation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Milton Academy Science Center</title>
		<link>/milton-academy-science-center/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2008 01:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=637</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Milton Academy Science Center William Rawn Associates Role: Design Intern 2008 Responsible for interior detailing for construction documents set.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Milton Academy Science Center</h4>
<h5>William Rawn Associates</h5>
<h5>Role: Design Intern</h5>
<h5>2008</h5>
<p></p>
<p>Responsible for interior detailing for construction documents set.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Double Doors</title>
		<link>/double-doors/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2007 05:11:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Environments]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=61</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Double Doors Harvard University Graduate School of Design Critic: Thomas Schroepfer 2007 How can a gate to an alleyway become a catalyst for activity? How can a wall become an inhabited space? Space in an alley between two gallery buildings is reconfigured dynamically by a grid of hollow columns hung on a moving track and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Double Doors</h4>
<h5>Harvard University Graduate School of Design</h5>
<h5>Critic: Thomas Schroepfer</h5>
<h5>2007</h5>
<p></p>
<p>How can a gate to an alleyway become a catalyst for activity?<br />
How can a wall become an inhabited space?</p>
<p>Space in an alley between two gallery buildings is reconfigured dynamically by a grid of hollow columns hung on a moving track and connected linearly in a tensegrity-like manner. The columns can be moved back and forth on the track to create a tight blockade against both pedestrians and traffic or to be distributed far apart to provide structure for installations. The columns can also be rotated 90 degrees along the track, from a vertical to a horizontal position. Moving one columns affects those attached to it along a line, and the pulley system allows a single person to move an entire row. The street is open to both pedestrians and traffic when all columns are in horizontal position.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Morgan Library Exhibition</title>
		<link>/book-mount/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2006 04:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Environments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Products]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=86</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Morgan Library Exhibition and Book Mount Imrey Culbert Atelier In collaboration with Craig Intinarelli Role: Project Designer 2005-2006 How can a mass-produced book mount be designed to fit the profile of a specific book? How can exhibition design re-imagine the relationship between viewer and artwork? For its grand re-opening exhibition after a large renovation and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Morgan Library Exhibition and Book Mount</h4>
<h5>Imrey Culbert Atelier</h5>
<h5>In collaboration with Craig Intinarelli</h5>
<h5>Role: Project Designer</h5>
<h5>2005-2006</h5>
<p></p>
<p>How can a mass-produced book mount be designed to fit the profile of a specific book?<br />
How can exhibition design re-imagine the relationship between viewer and artwork?</p>
<p>For its grand re-opening exhibition after a large renovation and addition by Renzo Piano, the Morgan Library wanted a book mount that would be representative of the institution. Book mounts are fabricated to fit the profile of a particular book held open to a specific page, and are generally made from extruded or heat-bent plexiglass or foam. They cannot be adapted to hold other books or even other pages within the same book. </p>
<p>Working closely with curators, conservators, and fabricators, we designed a book mount that was sturdy, modular and reusable. The design is composed of a kit of standardized parts that can be assembled to form a customized mount for each book. The bases and angles are created in a pre-set array of sizes to allow for as many types of books and positions as possible. </p>
<p>The Morgan Library’s collection of first edition manuscripts, original sheet music and artists’ sketches composed the bulk of its opening exhibition. The rarity and fragility of such artwork generally discourages visitors from coming too close and looking too deeply. The design of the tilted easel encouraged people to imagine themselves as the artist, to lean in and become more aware of the subtleties and textures of the art. </p>
<p>In addition to the design of the book mount, responsibilities included contributing to the design of the casework and working with curators to create the layout of the exhibition spaces. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shelf Screen</title>
		<link>/shelfscreen/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2006 07:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[veraseatonshur]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Products]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=64</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Screen/Shelf Independent Project 2005 How does a screen double as a storage unit? A screen doubles as a mutable, porous bookshelf that creates varied levels of privacy that change depending on its configuration. Two boards of 3/4” plywood are used to create the six sections of the screen and four shelves that sit within the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Screen/Shelf</h4>
<h5>Independent Project</h5>
<h5>2005</h5>
<p></p>
<p>How does a screen double as a storage unit?</p>
<p>A screen doubles as a mutable, porous bookshelf that creates varied levels of privacy that change depending on its configuration. Two boards of 3/4” plywood are used to create the six sections of the screen and four shelves that sit within the slots. The slots can also remain open for a greater degree of permeability. The unit can be laid flat or folded and stored when not in use.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
